Paul Muhia CV

https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulmuhia/ https://twitter.com/pablohmoha

Affiliations

https://www.aemda.org
https://www.raynowenergy.com/
http://www.powward.com/



pamnjoh@gmail.com



+254741173640, +254733859604

PROFILE: Registered Graduate Engineer, EBK. BSc. Electrical & Electronics Engineering

Expertise in the development and deployment of electric vehicles, energy access for productive use, and energy management with an understanding of the African market. I have co-founded 2 start-ups Powward developing electric 2 and 3 wheelers for sustainable transport solutions and Raynow energy to provide sustainable energy solutions including solar charging stations.

I am also leading the operations of the Association for Electric Mobility and Development in Africa (AEMDA) which is a an industry association providing a voice and platform for emobility companies in Kenya at the moment and progressing to East Africa and later rest of Africa.

KEY SKILLS

- Data analysis & market insights
- Project/product development, Implementation & management
- Financial analysis for project implementation
- Conduct general and investment grade energy
- Installation and commissioning of smart energy meters for monitoring energy consumption
- Measurement & Verification of energy efficiency projects using IPMVP
- Energy management using ISO 50001
- Familiar with technology in IoT, Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence

WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2021 - Present: Powward CEO

> At Powward we are developing locally electric 2 and 3 wheelers (Passenger and cargo)

January 2021 – Present: Raynow Energy CEO

June 2020 - Present: AEMDA Operations

January 2020 – Present: Energy 4 Impact Energy Access Analyst.

Duties and responsibilities:

- > Implement different energy access programmes
- > Support the development and growth of privately owned MSMEs that deliver renewable energy

products and services to the poor, mainly in rural and peri-urban areas.

- Provide support to SME clients on their business models, partnership facilitation, project development, investment readiness, financial modelling, and capital raising.
- Conduct market studies and research for SME clients, donors and internal knowledge generation, including desk research, primary and secondary research.
- Monitoring and Evaluation of both project specific and the impact indicators. Impact indicators include jobs creation, increase in energy consumption from renewable energy, CO2 emissions and increased income from productive use of the energy.
- Working with different stakeholders including government entities and identify ways of improving energy access both in rural and urban areas. This includes interventions that government can take up e.g., inclusion of the urban poor settlements in county plans for electrification.

June 2018 – January 2020: Eenovators Ltd. Energy Engineer.

Duties and responsibilities:

- Carrying out general and investment-grade energy audits to identify potential energy savings.
- > Recommendations on energy saving opportunities to clients.
- ➤ Benchmarking on IREE standards for financing projects through Energy Performance Contract (EPC) in the ESCO model.
- Eagles program team leader: spearheading reinvigoration of energy management program and marketing of the same.
- > Form and train energy committees
- Analysis of energy data and CO2 emissions.
- Energy audit automation: the standardized platform for energy efficiency projects, which will increase efficiency and attract foreign investors.
- > Real-time monitoring of electricity and water consumption for effective energy management.
- Carrying out site inspection and energy surveys.

Feb 2017 – April 2017: Burhani Engineers Ltd. **Engineering**

Intern. Duties and responsibility:

- Verification of Automatic Tank gauging, Vivo Nairobi terminal.
- Design and testing of Energy management system.
- Power line transmission & substation design, KTDA.

Feb 2016 – April 2016: County Government of Nairobi. **Engineering**

Intern. Duties:

- Installation & maintenance of street lighting.
- Repair & maintenance of electrical equipment.

ACHIEVEMENTS

April 2021: Co-founded Powward providing sustainable transport solutions with a vision of developing an effective vehicle for everyday use by individuals and businesses across Africa.

Jan 2021: Co-founded Raynow energy providing sustainable energy solutions inclusive solar charging stations.

June 2020: Initiated and spearheaded the development of the Association for Electric Mobility and

Development in Africa (AEMDA) bringing together all key stakeholders in accelerating the transition to electric mobility.

EDUCATION

2013 – 2018: Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

BSc. Electrical & Electronics Engineering

Grade: 2nd Upper-class Honors

2009 – 2012: Oloolua Secondary School

KCSE Grade: A -

2003-2008: Olteyani Primary School

KCPE Grade: 335 marks